Finding Aid for Summer Session (University of Michigan) records, 1902-1965
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Summer Session (University of Michigan) records 1902-1965
University of Michigan. Summer Session.
10 linear feet
8732 Bimu C361 2
Office administering summer session programs and camps of the University of Michigan. Executive committee and faculty minutes, student registers, correspondence, reports, budgets, and related administrative files; include papers relating to summer camps, notably the Biological Station, Camp Davis, Camp Filibert Roth, the Fresh Air Camp, and others.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donor no. 1036.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The records are open to research.
Office administering summer session programs and camps of the University of Michigan. Formally established in 1900, the office oversaw courses offered on campus as well instructional work at off-campus site including Biological Station, Camp Davis, Camp Filibert Roth, the Fresh Air Camp.s
The Summer Session records consist of executive committee and faculty minutes, student registers, correspondence, reports, budgets, and related administrative files; include papers relating to summer camps, notably the Biological Station, Camp Davis, Camp Filibert Roth, the Fresh Air Camp, and others.
Subjects:
Camp Davis (University of Michigan); Camp Filibert Roth (University of Michigan); Fresh Air Camp (University of Michigan); University of Michigan. Biological Station.
- Budgets, reports, correspondence
  - 1902-June 1919 (Box 1)
  - July 1919-1930 (Box 2)
  - 1931-1944 (Box 3)
- University camps
  - Biological Camp, 1913-1933 (Box 3)
  - Camp Davis, 1913-1933 (Box 3)
  - Geology and Geographical Camp, Mills Spring, Kentucky, 1919-1933 (Box 4)
  - Camp Filibert Roth, 1927-1933 (Box 4)
  - Fresh Air Camp, 1923-1925 (Box 4)
- Budgets and Regents communications
  - Budgets, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
  - Appointments, communications to the Board of Regents, 1950 (Box 4)
- Yearly Files
  (include budgets, enrollments, reports, summary of annual guidance workshop, etc.)
  - 1950-1953 (Box 4)
  - 1954-1956 (Box 5)
  - 1957-1959 (Box 6)
  - 1959 (cont.)-1961 (Box 7)
  - 1962-1965 (Box 8)
- Other records
  - Minutes of the executive committee of the summer session, 1945-1962 (Box 8)
  - Summarization of budgets, enrollments, etc., 1950s-1960s (Box 8)
  - Minutes of the executive committee of the summer session, 1945-1962
  - Summarization of budgets, enrollments, etc., 1950s-1960s
  - Field School of the Universities of California, Michigan, and Texas at the National University of Mexico (Box 10)
  - Summer School Student Records, 1894-1912, 2 volumes (Box 10)
  - Summer Session Faculty Minutes, 1896-1900, 1 volume (Box 10)
  - Committee on Tax Survey papers, 1928-1929, 1 folder (Box 10)
    (Summer Session Dean E.H. Kraus, chair.)
  - Scrapbook, Michigan Daily clippings on summers session excursions, 1934 (Box 10)
- Reports of seminars, workshops, and programs
  - U-M Peace Corps Training Program (Box 9)
  - Biological Station (Box 9)
  - University Fresh Air Camp (Box 9)
  - Inter-Institutional Seminar in Child Development (Box 9)
  - Field School of the Universities of California, Michigan, and Texas at the National University of Mexico (Box 9)
  - Conferences on Aging (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous other reports (Box 9)